# **Keith Lewis**

### **SUMMARY**

A self-taught Software Engineer with a varied experience whose programming languages include JavaScript, C#, Python, VBA, SQL (PL/SQL, T-SQL, Jet-SQL). Experience with technologies such as ASP.NET, REST, JSON, SOAP, XML, AJAX, CSS, HTML, Server 2003/2012, SQL Server 2005/2008 R2/2012. IIS 6/8, Oracle SQL, Access, Salesforce and unique experience with platforms such as Splunk.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Educational Development Corp - Sr Software Developer

November 2021 - Present

- Developed app from base in Blazor
- Resolved bugs and added functionality to ecommerce site
- Working remotely with little supervision
- Coached junior devs in proper software practices
- Assisted Jr devs with problematic issues

## **TEAMClinics - Sr. NET Developer (Contract)**

March 2021 - Nov 2021

- Rebuilding existing PHP site in ASP.NET
- Building new and converting existing functionalities to new site
- Working remotely with little supervision
- Interacting directly with C-Suite daily
- Assisting with release workflow of project to maintain smooth transition

## Trinity Computers (Business Application Development) – Owner/Lead Solutions Magician

March 2015 - Present

- Building .NET app to make it easier to find FOSS projects to submit your first PR to.
- CareerTrek Developing .NET Core app to assist job hunters with tracking applications, giving recruiters an easy view, and rating recruiters
- Planning .NET Core app that will be a multi-industry modular modern ERP solution
- Deploying applications to AWS

## Summit ESP - Developer III

May 2019 - March 2021

- Refactored Django/Angular app into a Flask/Vue App, Developed side-by-side with existing app
- Maintained and extended existing Django applications and developed Python scripts to meet business demands
- Maintained and created servers, networking stacks and ECS
- Utilised Travis CI to automate testing/validation
- Helped other devs understand database structure and helped onboard new devs
- Managed Git workflow of several projects

## Summit ESP - ERP Admin/Business Reporting

March 2017 - May 2019

- Administered Fishbowl, a custom Java ERP backed by Firebird. Added new users, maintained pricing rules.
- Developed Excel-based ODBC reports for users out of MySQL and Firebird and implemented a self-service reporting tool.
- Developed VBA automation for pulling SCADA data for wells out of a PostgreSQL database.
- Developed C# programs for data import and export from Fishbowl.
- Developed financial dashboard in Microsoft PowerBI and in QlikView.

150 Fox Run Circle, Jenks, OK 74037 **417-429-7601** 

kclewis0614@gmail.com

### LinkedIn

jacrys

**Github** 

jacrys

#### **StackOverflow**

jacrys

#### **Twitter**

jacrystalach

#### **SKILLS**

### .NET Framework

C#, Razor, ASP.NET MVC, Blazor, MudBlazor , NopCommerce, ASP.NET AJAX, Syncfusion, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Web API, WebForms, WinForms

### Web Development

Bootstrap, REST, SOAP, HTML5, Vue, React, AngularJS, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful WebServices

#### **SQL**

TSQL, PLSQL, Postgres, MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Access

#### **Servers**

Microsoft SQL Server 2008-2012, SSRS, Postgres, MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Access

### **Soft Skills**

Troubleshooting, Process Improvement, Leadership Development, Technical Support, Management, Lateral Thinking, Leadership

#### **Hard Skills**

Software Development, Process Improvement, Data Analysis

### Languages

C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, VBA, Ruby on Rails

#### **Data Formats**

XML, JSON

### **Collaboration Tools**

JIRA, Confluence, Github

## Avis Budget Group - Reporting Developer III

October 2014 - March 2017

- Developed e-mail survey invitation scheduling tool in C#, utilising customisable timing w/10% response rate that used JSON config files.
- Developed tracking tools utilising custom branching logic in C#, with logic that fully resets if user changes original responses.
- Developed cross-framework websites using modern web methodologies.
- Helped other devs with database structure and more jr devs with difficult issues
- Responsible for Server maintenance and performance

## Expedia - Hotel Systems Analyst Lead

July 2010 - October 2014

- Resolved issues with hoteliers' access to internal systems, appearance on partner websites and reservations processing incorrectly.
- Created and modified T-SQL queries to complete the duties at hand.
- Helped analysts understand database structure, and with hard issues
- Nurtured relationship with analysts, determining candidates for promotion
- Mentored candidates in leading and mentoring to ensure transition to Leads
- Saw a conversion rate of 5 out of 6 Lead candidates making Lead
- Developed an automation system for resolution of failed e-mail/ notifications, saving 40% - 60% in time and about \$35,000 yearly.
- Developed and implemented an automation system in VBA for assignment of analyst casework to mitigate out-of-order casework.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Project+ Certification** – Badge ffd7fd21-b0af-4e48-a4a7-17e537b7fc09 Issued 4 Sept 2019

**A+ Certification** – Badge e75a7734-ecf7-4723-a43b-02ba5706eb08 Issued 26 Feb 2020 - Expires 26 Feb 2023

### **TALKS**

## Pi Day: Making a RetroPi from a RaspberryPi-

Showing novices how to build a RetroPi

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RBmAswULRyQ 1 Nov 2018

### I want to contribute to OSS but don't know how-

**Encouraging contributions to FOSS** 

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FTM0iwclDqY 1 Nov 2018

## How to find issues to contribute to during Hacktoberfest-

Showing a tool to find issues to work on

https://youtu.be/3lmtgyuF2mg?t=855 1 Nov 2018

#### **VOLUNTEER**

## Free Code Camp

November 2017 - Present

Developer - I worked on development solutions for non-profit organizations in the course of completing online certifications.

### Code for America

May 2015 – Present

Volunteer Developer -

Assisted with project development and implementation for the Tulsa, OK affiliate.

### **Development Tools**

WSL, VS Code, Visual Studio 2010+

#### **EDUCATION**

## Western Governors University **Software Development**

Expected Sept 2023

### Free Code Camp **Computer Software Engineering**

December 2017

## Missouri Southern State University

**Pre-veterinary Medicine** 

December 2005

### Webb City High School **Biology**

December 2000